every person has their own nutritional
demands and um
taking care of them is extremely crucial
but what more important than
emphasizing on nutrition first we need
to emphasize to all people that food is
not just skate food is not just calories
and food is not just eaten because
um i'm hungry uh khanna is your fuel it
is information that you're giving your
body every bite that you put into your
mouth
is information information that takes
you towards good health or information
that takes you towards disease
so first and foremost we all need to
realize the importance of every bite
that we are putting into our mouth if we
want to stay in charge of our lives and
be multitaskers as we are gifted born
gifted to do we need to ensure that we
are equipping our body with the right
source of nutrition
all the way through so first and
foremost we have to highlight
khana
we will consume it coming to women's
needs our needs change with every decade
in our 20s importance has to be
different versus 30s 40s and 50s so
every decade has a new importance that
you need to give to whether it is one
particular nutrient calcium when you're
in your 20s because that's the bone
building stage
iron uh also in your puberty and bone
building stage uh proteins are a vital
nutrient that needs to be focused on all
throughout our lives because uh you a
woman's life plays a lot of roller
coasters in her
hormones and her nutritional demands and
what her body is doing from pregnancy to
breast feeding to
um
menopause our hormones go have a nice
joyride all the time so if you're not
going to eat according to the stage at
which you are you are going to be
inflicted by health problems whether
these are minor ones like um
no glow in your skin or hair fall or
brittle nails or low energy crankiness
mood swings or there are major ones like
diabetes blood pressure
cancers so you have to know the nutrient
of the need of the hour at every stage
and at every age
[Music]